Guide to the Rosetta Reitz Papers, 1929-2008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Reference Materials Series 1946-2005, (23 boxes)
  - Magazines and Journals
    - Record Research (July 1976) vol. 141 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (September 1976) vol. 142 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (December 1976) vol. 143 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (March 1977) vol. 144, 145 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (May/June 1977) vol. 146/147 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (July 1977) vol. 148 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (October 1977) vol. 149, 150 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (January 1978) vol. 151, 152 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (April 1978) vol. 153, 154 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (July 1978) vol. 155, 156 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (September 1978) vol. 157, 158 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (December 1978) vol. 159, 160 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (February/March 1979) vol. 161, 162 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (August 1979) vol. 165, 166 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (October 1979) vol. 167, 168 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (January 1980) vol. 169, 170 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (March 1980) vol. 171, 172 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (June 1980) vol. 173, 174 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (September 1980) vol. 175, 176 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (November 1980) vol. 177, 178 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (February 1981) vol. 179, 180 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (April 1981) vol. 181, 182 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (July 1981) vol. 183, 184 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (October 1981) vol. 185, 186 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (December 1981) vol. 187, 188 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (July 1982) vol. 191, 192 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (March/April 1983) vol. 197, 198 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (September 1983) vol. 201, 202 (Box 45)
    - Record Research (February 1985) vol. 211, 212 (Box 45)
    - Rhythm and News (n/a) vol. 941 (Box 45)
    - Rhythm and News (n/a) vol. 947 (Box 45)
    - Roundup (n/a) vol. 12 (Box 45)
    - Self-Help: A Health Resource Guide (1979) vol. 7 (Box 45)
    - Southland Blues (October 1994) vol. 5 no. 10 (Box 45)
    - Storyville (November 1965) vol. 1 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (December 1965) vol. 2 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (February 1966) vol. 3 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (April 1966) vol. 4 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (June 1966) vol. 5 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (August 1966) vol. 6 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (October 1966) vol. 7 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (December 1966) vol. 8 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (February 1967) vol. 9 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (April 1967) vol. 10 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (June 1967) vol. 11 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (August 1967) vol. 12 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (October 1967) vol. 13 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (December 1967) vol. 14 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (February 1968) vol. 15 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (April 1968) vol. 16 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (June 1968) vol. 17 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (October 1968) vol. 19 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (December 1968) vol. 20 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (February 1969) vol. 21 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (April 1969) vol. 22 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (June 1969) vol. 23 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (August 1969) vol. 24 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (October 1969) vol. 25 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (December 1969) vol. 26 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (February 1970) vol. 27 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (April 1970) vol. 28 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (June 1970) vol. 29 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (August 1970) vol. 30 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (October 1970) vol. 31 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (December 1970) vol. 32 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (April 1971) vol. 34 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (June 1971) vol. 35 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (August 1971) vol. 36 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (October 1971) vol. 37 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (December 1971) vol. 38 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (February 1972) vol. 39 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (April 1972) vol. 40 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (June 1972) vol. 41 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (August 1972) vol. 42 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (October 1972) vol. 43 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (December 1972) vol. 44 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (February 1973) vol. 45 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (April 1973) vol. 46 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (June 1973) vol. 47 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (August 1973) vol. 48 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (October 1973) vol. 49 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (December 1973) vol. 50 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (February 1974) vol. 51 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (April 1974) vol. 52 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (June 1974) vol. 53 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (August 1974) vol. 54 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (October 1974) vol. 55 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (December 1975) vol. 56 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (February 1975) vol. 57 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (April 1975) vol. 58 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (June 1975) vol. 59 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (August 1975) vol. 60 (Box 46)
    - Storyville (October 1975) vol. 61 (Box 47)
    - Storyville (December 1975) vol. 62 (Box 47)
    - Storyville (February 1976) vol. 63 (Box 47)
    - Storyville (April 1976) vol. 64 (Box 47)
    - Storyville (June 1976) vol. 65 (Box 47)
    - Storyville (August 1976) vol. 66 (Box 47)
    - Storyville (October 1976) vol. 67 (Box 47)
    - Storyville (December 1976) vol. 68 (Box 47)
    - Storyville (February 1977) vol. 69 (Box 47)
    - Storyville (April 1977) vol. 70 (Box 47)
    - Storyville (June 1977) vol. 71 (Box 47)
    - Storyville (August 1977) vol. 72 (Box 47)
    - Storyville (April 1978) vol. 76 (Box 47)
    - Strictly Nothing but the Blues (January 1991) vol. 19 (Box 47)
    - Tell a Woman (1972) vol. 6 (Box 47)
    - Tell It Like It Is (Summer 1996) vol. 1 no. 12 (Box 47)
    - Tell It Like It Is (Summer 1997) vol. 1 no. 13 (Box 47)
    - True Blues (July 1996) vol. 1 no. 1 (Box 47)
    - Unlimited Blues (January/February 1977) vol. 123 (Box 47)
    - Voices of Women (1985) (Box 47)
    - Westcoast Blues Review (June/July 1995) vol. 11 (Box 47)
    - Westcoast Blues Review (August/September 1995) vol. 12 (Box 47)
    - The Wire (December 1984) vol. 10 (Box 47)
    - The Wire (April 1985) vol. 14 (Box 47)
    - The Wire (May 1985) vol. 15 (Box 47)
    - The Wire (June 1985) vol. 16 (Box 47)
    - The Wire (July 1985) vol. 17 (Box 47)
    - Women in (E)Motion (September 1988) vol. 14 (Box 47)
    - Women: A Journal of Liberation (Spring 1970) vol. 1 no. 3 (Box 47)
  - Books
    Primarily related to music but some related to food and feminist issues. Includes the following books authored by Reitz: Mushroom Cookery (1965), Where to go in Greenwich Village (1971), and Menopause: a positive approach (1977) with Dutch and German translations.
    - Adegbalola, Gaye; Rabson, Ann. Saffire- the uppity blues women: songbook volume 2. Oberlin, Oh.: E and R Music Engravers, 1995. (Box 48)
    - Alberston, Chris. Bessie. New York: Stein and Day, 1972. (Box 48)
      (notes in margins) (extensive cover damage)
    - Alberston, Chris. Louis Armstrong. Alexandria, Vir.: Time-Life Records, 1978. (Box 48)
    - Allen, Frederick Lewis. Only yesterday: an informal history of the 1920's. New York: Harper and Row, 1964. (Box 48)
      (notes in margins)
    - Allen, Walter C.; Rust, Brain A .L. King Joe Oliver. Belleville, N.J.: Walter C. Allen, 1955. (Box 48)
    - Applebaum, Stanely; Camner, James. (ed.) Stars of the American musical theater in historic photographs: 361 protraits from the 1860's to 1950. New York: Dover, 1981. (Box 48)
    - Archer, Robyn; Simmonds, Diana. A star is torn. London: Virago, 1986. (Box 48)
    - Baker, Houston A. Black literature in America. New York: McGraw-Hill, 1971. (Box 48)
    - Balliett, Whitney. American singers. New York: Oxford, 1979. (Box 48)
    - Balliett, Whitney. New York notes: a journal of jazz, 1972-1975. Boston: Houghton Mifflin, 1976. (Box 48)
    - Bechet, Sidney. Treat it gentle: an autobiography. New York: Da Capo, 1978. (Box 48)
    - Bell, Roseann P.; Parker, Bettye J.; Guy-Sheftall, Beverly. Sturdy black bridges: visions of black women in literature. Garden City, N.Y.; Anchor Books, 1979. (Box 48)
    - Berendt, Joachim. The new jazz book: a history and guide. New York: Hill and Wang, 1962. (Box 48)
    - Bernhardt, Clyde E. B.; Harris, Sheldon. I remember: eighty years of black entertainment, big bands, and the blues. Philadelphia: University of Pennsylvania Press, 1986. (Box 48)
    - Berry, Faith. Langston Hughes: before and beyond Harlem. Westport, Conn.: Lawrence Hill, 1983. (Box 48)
      (inscription back endpaper)
    - Blesh, Rudi. Shining trumpets: a history of jazz. New York: Da Capo, 1946. (Box 48)
    - Blesh, Rudi; Janis, Harriet. They all played ragtime. New York: Oak, 1971. (Box 48)
    - Boeckman, Charles. Cool, hot and blue: a history of jazz for young people. New York: Washington Square Press, 1970. (Box 48)
    - Bogle, Donald. Toms, Coons, mulattoes, mammies, and bucks: an interpretive history of blacks in American films. New York: Bantam, 1974. (Box 48)
    - Bogle, Donald. Brown sugar: eighty years of America’s black female superstars. New York: Harmony Books, 1980. (Box 48)
      (notes in margins) (pp. 83, 84, 89, 90, 195, 196 defaced)
    - Bowers, Dwight Blocker. American musical theater: shows, songs, and stars. Washington, D.C.: Smithsonian Collection of Recordings, 1989. (Box 48)
    - Bradford, Perry. Born with the blues: Perry Bradford’s own story. New York: Oak, 1965. (Box 48)
      (notes in margins) (frontispiece, pp. 43, 44, 103, 104, 113, 114 defaced)
    - Breman, Paul. Blues: en andere wereldlijke volksmuziek van denoorddamerikaanse neger. Servire, 1961. (Box 48)
    - Bricktop; Haskins, James. Bricktop. New York: Atheneum, 1983. (Box 49)
    - Buckley, Gail Lumet. The Hornes: an American family. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1986. (Box 49)
      (inscription front endpaper)
    - Buerkle, Jack V.; Barker, Danny. Bourbon Street Black: the New Orleans black jazzman. New York: Oxford, 1973. (Box 49)
    - Case, Brian; Britt, Stan. The illustrated encyclopedia of jazz. New York: Harmony Books, 1978. (Box 49)
    - Cerulli, Dom; Korall, Burt; Nasatir, Mort. The jazz word. New York: Ballantine Books, 1960. (Box 49)
    - Charters, Samuel B.; Kunstadt, Leonard. Jazz: a history of the New York scene. New York: Da Capo, 1981. (Box 49)
    - Charters, Samuel. The poetry of blues. New York: Avon Books, 1963. (Box 49)
    - Charters, Samuel. The poetry of the blues. New York: Oak, 1963. (Box 49)
    - Charters, Samuel. Walking a blues road: a selection of blues writing 1956-2004. New York; London: Marion Boyars, 2004. (Box 49)
      (with note and signature by author)
    - Chilton, John. Billie's blues: Billie Holliday's story 1933-1959. New York: Stein and Day, 1975. (Box 49)
      (notes in margins) (extensive binding damage) (looose pages)
    - Chilton, John. Who's who of jazz: Storyville to Swing Street. Philadelphia; New York; London: Chilton Books, 1970. (Box 49)
      (notes in margins) (page of plates defaced) (loose pages)
    - Chilton, John. Jazz. Teach yourself series. Sevenoaks, Eng.: Hodder and Stoughton, 1979. (Box 49)
    - Chilton, John. Sidney Bechet: the wizard of jazz. New York: Oxford University Press, 1987. (Box 49)
    - Clarke, Donald. Wishing of the moon: the life and times of Billie Holiday. New York: Viking, 1994. (Box 49)
    - Colin, Sid. Ella: the life and times of Ella Fitzgerald. London: Elm Tree Books, 1986. (Box 49)
    - Collier, James Lincoln. Louis Armstrong: an American genius. New York: Oxford University Press, 1983. (Box 49)
      (notes in margins) (with note and signature by author)
    - Collier, James Lincoln. The great jazz artists. New York: Four Winds Press, 1977. (Box 49)
    - Cook, Bruce. Listen to the blues. New York: Charles Scribner’s Sons, 1973. (Box 49)
    - Cooper, Ralph; Dougherty, Steve. Amateur night at the Apollo: Ralph Cooper presents five decades of entertainment. New York: HarperCollins, 1990. (Box 50)
    - Costlow, Judy; Lopez, Maria Cristina; Taub, Mara. Menopause: a self-care manual. Santa Fe, N.M.: Santa Fe Health Education Project, 1989. (Box 50)
    - Count Basie; Murray, Albert (ed.). Good morning blues: the autobiography of Count Basie. New York: Primus, 1985. (Box 50)
    - Cripps, Thomas. Slow fade to black: the negro in American film, 1900-1942. London; Oxford; New York: Oxford Uiversity Press, 1977. (Box 50)
    - Dahl, Linda. Stormy weather: the music and lives of a century of jazzwomen. New York: Pantheon, 1984. (Box 50)
    - Dance, Stanley. The world of Earl Hines. New York: Charles Scribner’s Sons, 1977. (Box 50)
    - Dance, Stanley. The world of Count Basie. New York: Da Capo, 1980. (Box 50)
    - Davis, Angela Y. Blues legacies and black feminism: Gertrude "Ma" Rainey, Bessie Smith, and Billie Holiday. New York: Pantheon, 1998. (Box 50)
    - Day, Beth. The little professor of Piney Woods: the story of professor Laurence Jones. New York: Julian Messner, 1955. (Box 50)
    - Dexter, Dave. The jazz story from the '90's to the '60's. Englewood Cliffs, N.J.: Prentice-Hall, 1964. (Box 50)
    - Driggs, Frank; Lewine, Harris. Black beauty, white heat: a pictorial history of classic jazz 1920-1950. New York: William Morrow, 1982. (Box 50)
    - Eells, George; Musgrove, Stanley. Mae West. London: Robson Books, 1984. (Box 50)
      (notes in margins) (notes in endpaper)
    - Ellison, Ralph. Shadow and act. New York: Vintage, 1972. (Box 50)
      (notes in margins) (loose page)
    - Feather, Leonard. The book of jazz: from then till now. New York: Dell, 1976. (Box 50)
      (binding damage)
    - Feather, Leonard. The book of jazz: from then till now. New York: Bonanza Books, 1962. (Box 50)
      (duplicate)
    - Ferris, William. Blues from the Delta. New York: Doubleday, 1978. (Box 50)
    - Fox, Charles. The jazz scene. London; New York: Hamlyn, 1972. (Box 50)
    - Fox, Ted. Showtime at the Apollo. New York: Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1983. (Box 50)
    - Francis, Andre. Jazz. New York; London: Grove Press, 1960. (Box 51)
    - Friedwald, Will. Jazz Singing: America's great voices from Bessie Smith to bebop and beyond. New York: Collier Books, 1990. (Box 51)
    - Gammond, Peter. Scott Joplin and the ragtime era. New York: St. Martin's Press, 1975. (Box 51)
    - Garland, Phyl. The sound of Soul. New York: Pocket Books, 1971. (Box 51)
    - Garon, Paul and Beth. Woman with guitar: Memphis Minnie’s blues. New York: Da Capo, 1992. (Box 51)
    - Garon, Paul. Blues and the Poetic Spirit. London; Eddison Press, 1975. (Box 51)
    - Giddins, Gary. Riding on a blue note: jazz and American pop. New York; Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1981. (Box 51)
    - Gleason, Ralph J. Celebrating the Duke: and Louis, Bessie, Billie, Bird, Carmen, Miles, Dizzy, and other heroes. Boston; Toronto: Little, Brown, 1975. (Box 51)
    - Goddard, Chris. Jazz away from home. New York: Paddington, 1979. (Box 51)
    - Godrich, John; Dixon, Robert M.W. (comp.) Blues and Gospel Records 1902-1942. London: Storyville, 1969. (Box 51)
      (notes in margins) (extensive binding damage)
    - Gottlieb, William P. The golden age of jazz. New York: Da Capo, 1979. (Box 51)
      (signed by author)
    - Gourse, Leslie. Louis' Children: American jazz singers. New York: Quill, 1984. (Box 51)
    - Hadlock, Richard. Jazz masters of the twenties. New York: Collier Books, 1965. (Box 51)
    - Hammond, John. John Hammond on record: an autobiography with Irvin Townsend. New York: Summit Books, 1977 (Box 51)
    - Handy, D. Antoinette. Black women in American bands and orchestras. Metuchen, N.J.; London: Scarecrow Press, 1981. (Box 51)
      (notes in margins) (notes in front endpaper)
    - Haney, Lynn. Naked at the feast: a biography of Josephine Baker. New York: Dodd, mead and Company, 1981. (Box 51)
    - Harris, Rex. Jazz. Melbourne; London; Baltimore: Penguin, 1953. (Box 51)
    - Harris, Sheldon. Blues who’s who: a biographical dictionary of blues singers. New Rochelle, N.Y.: Arlington House, 1979. (Box 52)
      (handwritten list of artist names, front endpaper) (extensive spine damage)
    - Harrison, Max. Charlie Parker. Perpetua “kings of jazz” series. New York: A. S. Barnes, 1960. (Box 52)
    - Haskins, Jim. Queen of the blues: a biography of Dinah Washington. New York: William Morrow and Company, 1987. (Box 52)
    - Haskins, Jim. The cotton club. New York: Random House, 1977. (Box 52)
      (notes in margins) (pp. 149, 150 defaced)
    - Hasse, John Edward. Beyond category: the life and genius of Duke Ellington. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1993. (Box 52)
    - Hentoff, Nat. Jazz is. New York: Avon Books, 1978. (Box 52)
    - Hester, Mary Lee. Going to Kansas City. Sherman, Tex.: Early Bird, 1980. (Box 52)
    - Himes, Chester. A rage in Harlem. New York: Avon Books, 1965. (Box 52)
    - Hodeir, Andre. Jazz: its evolution and essence. New York: Grove Press, 1956. (Box 52)
    - Holiday, Billie; Dufty, William. Lady sings the blues. New York: Lancer, 1956. (Box 52)
    - Howard, John Tasker; Lyons, James. MusModernic: a popular guide to greater musical enjoyment. New York: The New American Library, 1957. (Box 52)
      (notes in margins) (binding damage)
    - Huggins, Nathaniel Irvin. Harlem Renaissance. London; Oxford; New York: Oxford University Press, 1971. (Box 52)
    - Hughes, Langston. Not without laughter. New York: Collier Books, 1969. (Box 52)
    - Hughes, Langston; Meltzer, Milton. Black magic: a pictorial history of black entertainers in America. New York: Bonanza, 1967. (Box 52)
      (pp. 83, 84, 181, 182 defaced)
    - Ingham, Chris. Billie Holiday. Divas series. London: Unanimous, 2000. (Box 52)
    - James, Etta; Ritz, David. Rage to survive: the Etta James story. New York: Villard, 1995. (Box 52)
    - Jepsen. Jorgen Grunnet. (ed.) Jazz Records: 1942-1965. vol. 1. Holte, Denmark: Karl Emil Knudsen, 1966. (Box 53)
    - Jepsen. Jorgen Grunnet. (ed.) Jazz Records: 1942-1965. vol. 2. Holte, Denmark: Karl Emil Knudsen, 1966. (Box 53)
    - Jepsen. Jorgen Grunnet. (ed.) Jazz Records: 1942-1967. vol. 4a. Holte, Denmark: Karl Emil Knudsen, 1968. (Box 53)
    - Jepsen. Jorgen Grunnet. (ed.) Jazz Records: 1942-1968. vol. 4c. Copenhagen, Denmark: Karl Emil Knudsen, 1970. (Box 53)
    - Jepsen. Jorgen Grunnet. (ed.) Jazz Records: 1942-1969. vol. 4d. Copenhagen, Denmark: Karl Emil Knudsen, 1970. (Box 53)
    - Jepsen. Jorgen Grunnet. (ed.) Jazz Records: 1942-1967. vol. 4b. Copenhagen, Denmark: Karl Emil Knudsen, 1969. (Box 53)
    - Jepsen. Jorgen Grunnet. (ed.) Jazz Records: 1942-1962. vol. 5. Holte, Denmark: Karl Emil Knudsen, 1963. (Box 53)
    - Jepsen. Jorgen Grunnet. (ed.) Jazz Records: 1942-1962. vol. 8. Holte, Denmark: Karl Emil Knudsen, 1965. (Box 53)
    - Jepsen. Jorgen Grunnet. (ed.) Jazz Records: 1942-1962. vol. 7. Holte, Denmark: Karl Emil Knudsen, 1964. (Box 53)
    - Jepsen. Jorgen Grunnet. (ed.) Jazz Records: 1942-1965. vol. 3. Holte, Denmark: Karl Emil Knudsen, 1967. (Box 53)
    - Jepsen. Jorgen Grunnet. (ed.) Jazz Records: 1942-1962. vol. 6. Holte, Denmark: Karl Emil Knudsen, 1963. (Box 53)
    - Johnson, James Weldon. Black Manhattan. New York: Atheneum, 1977. (Box 53)
    - Johnson, James Weldon. God's trombones: seven negroes in verse. Middlesex, Eng.: Penguin, 1976. (Box 53)
    - Jones, Hettie. Big star fallin' mama: five women in black music. New York: Viking Press, 1974. (Box 53)
      (image defaced) (loose page)
    - Jones, LeRoi. Blues people: negro music in white America. New York: William Morrow, 1963. (Box 53)
    - Jones, Max; Chilton, John. Louis: the Louis Armstrong story 1900-1971. Boston; Toronto: Little, Brown, 1971. (Box 53)
    - Kay, George W. Those fabuolous Gennetts!: the life story of a remarkable record label. New Orleans: New Orleans Jazz Museum, 1953. (Box 53)
    - Keepnews, Orin; Grauer, Bill. (comp.) A pictorial history of jazz: people and places form New Orleans to modern jazz. New York: Crown, 1966. (Box 53)
    - Keil, Charles. Urban blues. Chicago; London: The University of Chicago Press, 1966. (Box 53)
      (notes in margins, front endpaper)
    - Kimball, Robert; Bolcom, William. Reminiscing with Sissle and Blake. New York: Viking, 1973. (Box 53)
      (pp. 155, 156 defaced)
    - Kinkle, Roger. The complete encyclopedia of popular and jazz music 1900-1950. vol. 1 New Rochelle, N.Y.: Arlington House, 1974. (Box 53)
    - Kislan, Richard. The Musical: a look at the American musical theater. Englewood Cliffs, N.J.: Prentice-Hall, 1980. (Box 54)
    - Lerner, Gerda. (ed.) Black women in white America: a documentary history. New York: Vintage, 1972. (Box 54)
    - Levine, Lawrence. Black culture and black consciousness: Afro-American folk thought from slavery to freedom. Oxford; London; New York: Oxford University Press, 1977. (Box 54)
    - Lieb, Sandra. Mother of the blues: a study of Ma Rainey. The University of Massechussetts Press, 1981. (Box 54)
      (with note and signature by author) (notes in margins) (extensive cover damage)
    - Lomax, Alan. Mister Jelly Roll: the fortunes of Jelly Roll Morton, New Orleans Creole and “inventor of jazz.” New York: Grove, 1950. (Box 54)
    - Machlin, Milt. Libby. New York: Tower Books, 1980. (Box 54)
    - Maddocks, Melvin. Giants of jazz: Billie Holiday. Alexandria, Vir.: Time-Life Records, 1979. (Box 54)
    - McCarthy, Albert. Big band jazz. New York: Berkley, 1974. (Box 54)
    - Meeker, David. Jazz in the movies: a guide to jazz musicians 1917-1977. New Rochelle, N.Y.: Arlington House, 1977. (Box 54)
    - Meier, August; Rudwick, Elliott. From plantation to ghetto. American century series. New York: Hill and Wang, 1966. (Box 54)
    - Mellers, Wilfrid. Music in a new found land: themes and developments in the history of American music. New York: Hillstone, 1964. (Box 54)
    - Mezzrow, Milton "Mezz"; Wolfe, Bernard. Really the blues. New York: Dell, 1946. (Box 54)
      (extensive binding damage) (loose pages)
    - Mills, Earl. Dorothy Daindridge: a portrait in black. Los Angeles: Holloway House, 1970. (Box 54)
    - Moore, Carman. Somebody's angel child: the story of Bessie Smith. New York: Dell, 1969. (Box 54)
    - Morgenstern, Dan. An Outline History of Jazz: The Jazz Story. New York: N.Y. Jazz Museum, 1973. (Box 54)
    - Morris, James R.; Taylor, J. R.; Bowers, Dwight Blocker (comp.). Six decades of songwriters and singers. American popular song series. Washington, D.C.: Smithsonian Collection of Recordings, 1984. (Box 54)
    - Myrus, Donald. Ballads, blues, and the big beat. New York: Macmillan, 1966. (Box 54)
    - New York Recording Laboratories (comp). The paramount book of blues. Port Washington, Wis.: New York Recording Laboratories. (Box 54)
    - Nicholson, Stuart. Billie Holliday. Boston: Northeastern University Press, 1995. (Box 54)
    - Oakely, Giles. The devil's music: a history of the blues. New York; London: Harvest/ HBJ Book, 1976. (Box 54)
    - Oliver, Paul. The Blackwell guide to recorded blues. Oxford; Cambridge, Mass.: Blackwell Publishers, 1991. (Box 55)
    - Oliver, Paul. Kings of jazz: Bessie Smith. New York: A.S. Barnes, 1959. (Box 55)
    - Oliver, Paul. The story of the blues. Radnor, Pa.: Chilton Book Co., 1969. (Box 55)
      (pp. 61-66, 109,110 defaced)
    - Oliver, Paul. The meaning of the blues. New York: Collier Books, 1960. (Box 55)
    - Ostransky, Leroy. Jazz city: the impact of our cities on the development of jazz. Englewood Cliffs, N.J.: Prentice-Hall, 1978. (Box 55)
    - Panassié, Hugues; Gautier, Madeleine. Guide to jazz. Boston: Houghton Mifflin, 1956. (Box 55)
      (two pages of plates defaced)
    - Pannassie, Hugues. Louis Armstrong. New York: Charles Scribner’s Sons, 1971. (Box 55)
    - Parks, Gordon. A choice of weapons. New York: Berkely Publishing Corporation, 1966. (Box 55)
    - Pavletich, Aida. Rock-a-bye, baby. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday and Company, 1980. (Box 55)